https://www.escmid.org/privacy_statement/

The Lancet / ESCMID Conference
ESCMID/FEMS Conference:
Archive
ABC Calc (AMC Tool)
EUCIC goes to help
Educational events for families to understand resistance and HAI’s
Collaborative Centres
About Collaborative Centres (ECCs)
About Mentorship Programme
About Mentorship Centres (EMCs)
ESCMID Parity Resource Tool
Just To Start...
TAE Steering Committee elections
Why nominate?
TAE Day 2017
Speciality training (UEMS)
Publications 2016
Clinical Microbiology and Infection (CMI)
Complete Interview
Privacy NoticeThe European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, (Europäische Gesellschaft für klinische Mikrobiologie und Infektionskrankheiten) (hereinafter "ESCMID", "we", "us" or "our") is committed to protecting the privacy and security of the personal information that is provided to us or collected by us during the course of our business. We store and process personal information in accordance with the Swiss Data Protection Act and, to the extent applicable, the EU General Data Protection Regulation. This privacy notice (hereinafter "Privacy Notice") explains how we collect and use any personal information that we obtain about you, and your rights in relation to that information when you visit our websites, enter into a business or other relationship with us, and participate in any of our events, including our on-site or virtual conferences (hereinafter "Event(s)"). We may provide you with additional privacy notices where we believe that it is appropriate to do so. Those additional notices supplement, and should be read together with, this Privacy Notice.
Overview Who is responsible for your personal informationHow we collect and use your personal informationOrganization, development and execution of the EventsBusiness development and business acceptanceUse of Event websites or platformsRegistration for our newsletter and information on the EventsOther contactsOur basis for processing your personal information	How and why we may share your personal information	How we protect your personal information	How long we keep your personal data	Your rights	Updates to this Privacy Notice  1.	Who is responsible for your personal information? ESCMID, P.O. Box 214, 4010 Basel, Switzerland, is responsible for your personal information provided to us or collected by us during the course of our business. As of 25 May 2018, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) sets new definitions for how to handle personal data. ESCMID takes the responsibility for the data we collect and store from our members very seriously and is dedicated to fulfil all of the GDPR’s requirements. 2. 	How we collect and use your personal information We collect and process your personal information as follows: 2.1 	Organization, development and execution of the Events
We collect personal information about attendees, participants, speakers, chairpersons, sponsors, endorsers and other third parties, as part of the organization, development and execution of the Events.
In order to provide you with our services for registered users and members, ESCMID collects and stores personal data from its registered users and members. We only collect information that is required for the specific purposes ESCMID offers, store it in secured databases and make sure to delete outdated user data ultimately. The types of personal information we may collect for this purpose include your name, contact details (such as your address, e-mail address, telephone and mobile numbers), your date of birth, the name of the organisation you work for, the contact details of your organisation, your curriculum vitae, references, and other information with which you provide us to participate, attend, speak, chair, sponsor, endorse or otherwise support the Events, as well as information of all kind from correspondence, contacts, and interactions with us relating to the Events.
We will also process information of all kind that is revealed to us in the course of the Events organized, developed and executed by us, which may include questions you ask or comments or other content and material you post or upload during video presentations, discussions or virtual and Q&A sessions and your participation in the Events. If you are not sure whether your interaction with us falls under one of the items mentioned before or you have interacted with us in another way, and you would like to know whether we have collected any personal information about you in this regard, feel free to contact us at info[at]escmid.org to know more. We collect personal information directly from you, related organisations, or other persons and their respective representatives or employees. We may receive or collect personal information from third persons such as your employer, other organisations that you have dealings with, or regulators or government agencies. We may also collect personal information from publicly available sources. We may use this information to provide all services in connection with the organization, development and execution of the Events, to fulfil our mission, to conduct, monitor, or analyse our business (e.g. administrative or operational processes), to improve our services in connection with present and future Events, and more generally to offer additional educational services.2.2 Business development and business acceptance We collect personal information about attendees, participants, speakers, chairpersons as well as other business contacts of the sponsors or endorsers of the Events as part of the development of other initiatives, conferences, or our mission.
The types of personal information we may collect include your name, contact details (such as your address, e-mail address, telephone and mobile numbers), your date of birth, the name of the organisation you work for, the contact details of your organisation, your curriculum vitae, references, feedback, comments, questions and other content with which you provide us, relating to the Events, or other interactions you have with us. We obtain this information directly from you, from other contacts, or from publicly available sources. We may use your personal information to maintain and develop our relationship with you, identify services you may be interested in, pursue certain mission development initiatives, send you publications and marketing communications, and invite you to other Events. You can control the information you receive through our marketing communications by using the corresponding option at the bottom of our e-mails. If you no longer wish to receive e-mails relating to our mission, services or Events, you can unsubscribe at any time by using such option at the bottom of the e-mail or by replying to info[at]escmid.org. 2.3 	Use of Event websites or platforms We collect, store and process certain personal information when you visit our general website as well as the Event websites or platforms (hereinafter "Websites"), contact us through a contact form or by e-mail, and use cookies on our Websites. The types of personal information we may collect include your name, e-mail address, address, affiliation with a scientific organisation, or IP-address. Relating to your interaction with our Websites, we gather information on what you click on, from where you were directed to the Websites, a history of your visits, and other information you voluntarily share with us when using these Websites. Please note that some of that information is indispensable for processing your requests.
We obtain this information either directly from you or through the use of cookies. We use cookies to collect information when you access our Websites. In particular, we use cookies to process your requests, when you contact us, when you subscribe to a newsletter, for the analysis of our website traffic, and for marketing communication purposes. You can set your cookie preferences when you visit our website for the first time, and later change them by following these links:Click here to install the opt-out cookie.Cookies are small text files that are placed in browser directories on your computer or mobile device when you visit our Websites. Our Websites use session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies enable our Websites to remember any information you have already entered when you move from page to page within one of our Websites. A session cookie is deleted either when you close your browser or after a short time. Persistent cookies allow the Websites to remember your preferences and settings when you visit the Websites in the future. Persistent cookies expire after a set period of time. We use cookies in the following ways: Google Analytics: We use Google Analytics, which provides us with information about how visitors use our Websites. Google uses cookies as part of the process to collect anonymized information, such as the number of visitors to the Websites, where they are from, the pages they visit and the length of time they have spent on our Websites. E-mail updates: Our marketing communications use cookies and tracking technology which help us to assess whether our e-mail updates have been opened, replied to, forwarded, the links provided therein clicked on, and also allow you to contact us via an online contact form. Social plugin: We use plugins for the social networks Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook and Youtube. You can recognise the plugins by the logos of the social networks which are placed on our Websites. If you interact with these social networks, the relevant information will be forwarded and your visit recognised by Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook and Youtube. Please note that we have no control over these social networks and the data they collect. For more information on how they process your data, we kindly refer you to their respective privacy policies.  You can change your browser settings to block cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent to your device. Please note that if you decide to disable cookies, you may not be able to access certain functions of our Websites or marketing communications.
2.4 	Registration for our newsletter and information on the Events We collect, store and process certain personal information such as your name and e-mail address when you register for our newsletter or sign up to receive further information on the Events. 2.5 	Other contacts Further, we collect and process information about you if you offer or provide products or services to us, if we evaluate your products or services, and generally when you request information from us or provide information to us.
3. 	Our basis for processing your personal information We will only use your personal information if and to the extent that applicable law allows us to do so. We will therefore process your personal information only if: it is necessary for the performance of a contract with you or the organisation you work for; it is necessary in connection with a legal obligation; you have given your consent (where necessary) to such use or the organisation you work for has obtained your consent (where necessary) to share your information with us; or we or a third party have a legitimate interest in processing your personal information which is not overridden by your interests or your rights and freedoms. When we rely on such a legitimate interest and you would like to know more about how we balanced our and your interests, you can contact us at info[at]escmid.org. 4. 	How and why we may share your personal information For some of our services related to the ESCMID membership, awards, research funding and so forth we work with trusted third parties. Your data is processed by these partners exclusively for the purpose of providing the aforementioned services and won’t be shared with any other party. In accordance with the GDPR, we conclude contracts to order data processing with each of our partners. All of our partners are located within the EU and are bound to the GDPR and ESCMID’s security requirements. We may share your personal information collected in the course of the Events with third persons (such as affiliates, sponsors, IT providers, vendors, service providers and other persons or organisations) in Switzerland, the EU or other countries if required or useful for providing our products and services. Further, we may share your personal information with third persons where: you have consented to us doing so (where necessary) or the organisation that you work for has obtained your consent for us to do so (where necessary); we are under a legal, regulatory or professional obligation to do so (for example, to comply with anti-money laundering or sanctions requirements); or it is necessary in connection with legal proceedings or in order to exercise or defend legal rights. We use third parties who provide products and services on our behalf and may share your information with them. These third parties include banks, insurance companies or technology suppliers. They may have access to your personal information when providing support.
5. 	How we protect your personal information We have put in place appropriate security measures to hold your personal information securely in electronic and physical form, to protect it from unauthorised access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorised modification or unlawful destruction or accidental loss. The participation in the Events is access controlled by your personal login and password authentication. Our employees and third party service providers who have access to confidential information (including personal information) are subject to confidentiality obligations.
6. 	How long we keep your personal data We will retain your personal information at least for as long as it is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. We will further retain your personal information to comply with legal and regulatory obligations, for as long as claims could be brought against us and for as long as legitimate interests, including data security, require us to do so.
7. 	Your rights The GDPR gives our members the right to ask for information regarding the personal data we store from them. Please feel free to contact our data security officers at info[at]escmid.org to review all your data we store from you as a member. You can quit your membership at any time. All your personal data we’ve stored to that point will then get deleted ultimately.In relation to the processing of your personal information you have rights that you can exercise under certain circumstances. These rights are to: request access to your personal information and certain information in relation to their processing; request rectification of your personal information; request the erasure of your personal information; request that we restrict the processing of your personal information; and object to the processing of your personal information.  If you have provided your consent to the collection, processing or transfer of your personal information for a specific purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time. Once we have received notification that you have withdrawn your consent, we will no longer process your information for the purpose or purposes you originally agreed to. We may refuse to provide access if the relevant data protection legislation or other legislation allows or obliges us to do so, in which case we will provide reasons for our decision as required by the law. If you would like to exercise these rights, please contact us in writing by e-mail at info[at]escmid.org or by letter to: ESCMID Executive OfficeP.O. Box 214 4010 Basel Switzerland  You will not, in general, have to pay a fee to exercise any of your individual rights. However, we may charge a fee for access to your personal information if the relevant data protection legislation allows us to do so, in which case we will inform you as required by the law. If you feel we have not handled your query or concern to your satisfaction, you can contact the competent data protection authority in Switzerland, the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (http://www.edoeb.admin.ch). 8. 	Updates to this Privacy Notice We reserve the right to update and change this Privacy Notice from time to time in order to reflect any changes to the way in which we process your personal information or changing legal requirements. Any changes we may make to the Privacy Notice in the future will be posted on this website. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to the Privacy Notice.    Basel, 17 September 2020
Members & Organisation
Research & Projects
Profession & Career
Dates & Events
Guidelines & Publications
News & Media
ESCMIDeLibraryMaterial from ESCMID education courses, summer schools, workshops and ECCMID conferencesread more  ESCMIDWeekly NewsYou can use this form to subscribe to the ESCMID newsletter or request a link to change your subscription settings.Sign UpSUBSCRIBEOur Network  CMI WEBSITE  EUCASTESCMID Member BenefitsReduced Fees
for EventsActive
ParticipationVoting
RightsJournal
SubscriptionsEligibility
for ProgrammesEligibility for Awards
and Grantsprofit from the member benefits ESCMID Member BenefitsReduced Fees
for EventsActive
ParticipationVoting
RightsJournal
SubscriptionsEligibility
for ProgrammesEligibility for Awards
and Grantsprofit from the member benefits ECCMID 202131st ECCMID
9-12 July 2021 Vienna, AustriaWe invite you to the 31st European Congress of Clinical Microbiology & Infectious DiseasesRead moreSITEMAP Members & OrganisationAbout ESCMIDESCMID YearbookMembershipESCMID FellowsPartnersJobs at ESCMIDResearch & ProjectsECCMIDESCMID ConferencesStudy GroupsEUCICEUCASTCOVID-19 Resource CentreFighting ResistancePipeline CornerNetworking CornerEmerging Infections Task ForceECRAIDProfession & CareerAwards & GrantsObserverships & Collaborative CentresEducational activitiesMentorshipsParity CommissionTrainee Association of ESCMIDSpeciality training (UEMS)ESCMID Visiting Professorship ProgrammeJobs in CM & IDDates & EventsESCMID DeadlinesCalendarESCMID CoursesESCMID ConferencesESCMID Summer SchoolECCMIDCalendar archiveGuidelines & PublicationsGuidelinesESCMID eLibraryPublicationsClinical Microbiology and Infection (CMI)Manual of MicrobiologyECCMID Abstract BookWhite papersCopyrightNews & MediaNewsPress releasesNewsletter Sign UpESCMID NewsletterMedia informationArchiveContact usESCMID Executive OfficeP.O. Box 2144010 BaselSWITZERLAND Phone +41 61 5080 173info[at]escmid.org Visiting addressESCMIDGerbergasse 143rd floor4010 BaselSWITZERLAND© ESCMID 2020. All rights reserved ESCMID.ContactSitemapPrivacy StatementDisclaimer Use of cookiesBy using this website, you agree to its use of cookies. ESCMID uses cookies to collect data about the use of its website and to improve its services.I agreeMore information
MY PROFILE
Personal Information
Membership Status
Membership Duration until11 December 2020
Personal Navigation
My Profile
ECC Administrator
X
